<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:base="http://tadpol.org/feed.atom" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Tadpol's bog</title>
  <id>http://tadpol.org/feed.atom</id>
  <link href="feed.atom" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tadpol.org" rel="alternate"/>
  <icon>/favicon.ico</icon>
  <updated>2012-04-04T09:06:40-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Michael Conrad Tadpol Tilstra</name>
  </author>
  <rights>All rights reserved.</rights>
  <generator>WebSpace 0.1 ruby code written by Michael Conrad Tadpol Tilstra</generator>
  <entry xml:base="projects//">
    <title>Avrian Jump</title>
    <link href="AvrianJump.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/http://tadpol.org/projects/AvrianJump.html</id>
    <published>2012-02-02T10:44:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-04-04T09:06:34-05:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<p><a href="images/avrianjump.jpg" class="thickbox" rel="projectsAvrianJumphtml"><img src="images/avrianjump-thumb.jpg" height="240" alt="Arduino with Audioino and a MacBook running Safari and Avrian Jump" width="320" /></a></p>

<p>A very simple ladder language for programming ATMega168s from a web browser.</p>

<p>This started out as a desire to be able to program an <a href="http://www.arduino.cc/">Arduino</a> from an iOS device.  Since it
doesn&#8217;t seem like compiler tools of any sort would get into the app store, I figured something
would need to be done in HTML5.  And if a <a href="http://bellard.org/jslinux/">PC emulator</a> could be written in javascript,
so could something like this.</p>

<p>However, recreating the Arduino IDE in HTML seemed like too much work, at least for a first
try.  So I reduced the project into something much simpler, while still putting real machine
code into the AVR&#8217;s flash.  A simple ladder language that compiled into AVR assembly, which
would be assembled into machine code, seemed like like a resonable reduction.  With that I
could take advantage of the <a href="http://www.hobby-roboter.de/forum/viewtopic.php?f=4&amp;t=128&amp;p=531">Audioino</a> bootloader, to load right from the web page.</p>

<h2>Download</h2>

<p><a href="http://github.com/tadpol/Avrian-Jump">Avrian Jump</a> is on <a href="http://github.com/">GitHub</a>, so head over there to
look at it.</p>

<h2>The Ladder</h2>

<p>Each rung on the ladder has a single test and multiple actions.  Tests can check the digital
pins, analog pins, and a couple of variables.  Each action can set a digital pin, a PWM output,
or a variable.  Analog, PWM, and variables are 16bit values.</p>

<p>There is no &#8216;setup()&#8217;.  Analog pins are always analog inputs.  When specified in a test, a
digital pin is set to an input then read.  When specified in an action, it is set to an output
then set.</p>

<p>PWM code is still non-existant, so how this will actually work is up in the air.  How I want it
to work is:  Specifying a pin in an action as a PWM output makes it a PWM output.  Specifying a
pin in a test stops it from doing PWM output.  Specifying a digital state for the pin in an
action also stops it from doing PWM output.</p>

<p>There is an ascii format of the ladders.  This was done because it seemed like it could be neat
to be able to tweet ladders.  You can view the ascii format, and also load ladders from it.
The ascii parser skips anything it doesn&#8217;t recognise; it is a bit too forgiving at times.</p>

<p>An example program:</p>

<pre><code>#Fast Blink LED
:T;A+=1
:A=16383;D13=1
:A=32767;D13=0,A=0
</code></pre>

<p>Mostly though, a ladder is converted into AVR assembly.</p>

<h2>The Assembler</h2>

<p>The assembler is pretty basic. Lots of features commonly found in other assemblers are
currently missing.  It does assemble the mneonics from <a href="http://www.atmel.com/atmel/acrobat/doc0856.pdf">Atmel&#8217;s pdf</a> into machine code.
It supports labels, but not local labels.  It has simple parameter replacement, so common names
can be defined for IO registers and memory regions and things.  It can also specify where in
memory to put the machine code, and can specify immeadiate words to save in the machine code.</p>

<p>This assembler doesn&#8217;t know about the various AVR devices, and so will happily assemble any of
the known mnemonics into the output.  Even if your target device has no idea what to do with
them.  It has assembled blink tests for the ATmega168 and the ATTiny13, so it seems pretty
flexable. (Avrian Jump currently only supports the ATmega168 though.  Maybe add others in the
future, but would have to figure the bootloader thing out first.)</p>

<h2>Outputs</h2>

<p>A ladder can be compiled into a few different formats:</p>

<ul>
<li>ASCII
<ul>
<li>This the only form can can be converted back into a ladder.</li>
<li>This is for sharing your ladder with others, or saving a ladder for later.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>S19
<ul>
<li>If you don&#8217;t have an <a href="http://www.hobby-roboter.de/forum/viewtopic.php?f=4&amp;t=128&amp;p=531">Audioino</a> bootloader, but still want to use a ladder.  A S19 can be
saved as a file, and loaded with <a href="http://ladyada.net/learn/avr/avrdude.html">avrdude</a>.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>WAV
<ul>
<li>A <a href="http://www.hobby-roboter.de/forum/viewtopic.php?f=4&amp;t=128&amp;p=531">Audioino</a> compatible wav file for loading the ladder onto an ATmega168 with the
<a href="http://www.hobby-roboter.de/forum/viewtopic.php?f=4&amp;t=128&amp;p=531">Audioino</a> bootloader installed.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Assembler
<ul>
<li>This is mostly around for debugging the ladder compiler.  It can be interesting to look at
too.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
            </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="projects//">
    <title>Tea</title>
    <link href="tea.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/http://tadpol.org/projects/tea.html</id>
    <published>2012-01-27T13:29:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2012-01-27T13:39:12-06:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<p>I&#8217;ve been playing with writing my own little scripting language for a bit now.  To keep it
interesting, I decided it needed to be very small.  The idea being is that I might be able to
use it in some of the micro-controller work I do.  Often it would be nice on those to just do a
little /something/ without having to stop, re-compile, and run.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve also been a bit bad, and not used revision control.  Hence this is the 18th time I created
a new directory for it.  </p>

<p>I cannot remember why I call it Tea.  There was a reason, I&#8217;m pretty sure, but the name is
stuck.</p>

<p>Also been playing with <a href="http://github.com">github</a>, so its over there if you want to see. 
<a href="http://github.com/tadpol/Tea">Tea18</a></p>
            </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="recipes//">
    <title>Quick Coleslaw</title>
    <link href="quickcoleslaw.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/http://tadpol.org/recipes/quickcoleslaw.html</id>
    <published>2003-03-29T13:00:04-06:00</published>
    <updated>2011-03-23T14:03:33-05:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">


<p>Start with equal parts Mayonnaise and a Vinaigrette dressing (<small>Most any kind will work</small>).  Mix, adjusting each until it is at a consistency you like.  Pour over chopped cabbage.  Mix well, coating everything.  Consume.</p>
            </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="recipes//">
    <title>Basic Pesto</title>
    <link href="BasicPesto.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/http://tadpol.org/recipes/BasicPesto.html</id>
    <published>2011-03-23T14:03:32-05:00</published>
    <updated>2011-03-23T14:03:32-05:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<table class="recipe">
  <tr>
    <td>Amount</td>
    <td>Measure</td>
    <td>Ingredient &#8212; Preparation</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>2</td>
    <td>cups</td>
    <td>
fresh basil leaves    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>2</td>
    <td></td>
    <td>
garlic cloves — chopped    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>2</td>
    <td>ounces</td>
    <td>
pine nuts    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>1/4</td>
    <td>tsp</td>
    <td>
Salt    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td></td>
    <td></td>
    <td>
pepper    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>1/2</td>
    <td>cup</td>
    <td>
Parmesan cheese    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>1/2</td>
    <td>cup</td>
    <td>
olive oil    </td>
  </tr>
</table>


<p>Put the basil, olive oil, pine nuts, garlic cloves and salt in the
blender or food processor, (I use the food processor), and mix at high
speed. Stop from time to time and scrape the ingredients down toward the
bottom with a rubber spatula. Add the cheese and grind until thoroughly
blended.</p>
            </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog//">
    <title>I bought a Town Home</title>
    <link href="townhome.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/http://tadpol.org/bog/townhome.html</id>
    <published>2004-03-23T19:09:20-06:00</published>
    <updated>2011-03-23T14:02:34-05:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">



<p>
It is a very strange surreal feeling.  The combinational effect of not
only buying something this big, but that someone is willing to give me
the money for it.  Or something like that.  Clearly, if I fail to pay
up, they just take the house back.  But I'm not really thinking about
that.  Too far gone in the mind.  The house is mine.
(<small>sorta</small>)
</p><p>
The one thing in the process that still is somewhat amazing is the
amount of paper work.  Or rather, the volumes of things that I must sign
or initial.  I think I shall be most forever entertained by getting a
document that says that I was in fact told about another document. 
Signing the first to proved that I was truly in fact told about the next
document.  Being given the next document immediately after signing the
prior, and signing it.  Its just funny in an odd sort of way.
</p><p>
Amidst the excitement there are a few standing concerns at the moment. 
Oddly, the largest of which is that I'll now be far enough out that I
will have to commute via car or bus.  No longer close enough to work to
walk when the weather permits.  The important thing here is that it is
not the commute that is bothering me, it is that I'll lose my free
exercise of walking about thirty minutes a day.
</p><p>
I will have to be diligent once moved.  Most probably in a combination
of doing exercise just to exercise, and eating less than I do now.  I am
not too worried about the eating, I have always been rather good at just
stopping when I felt full.  (<small>It has never bothered me to leave
food on my plate.  When I'm done eating, I'm done.</small>)  It is the
whole remembering to take to move a bunch.
</p><p>
And this is where I'm hoping my new location that will be roughly the
right distance from book stores and the like.  The distance being just
enough that it is exercise to walk there, but not so much that it feels
overly far away to travel by foot.  So I figure I'm ok at least one day
of the week.  It is then the remaining two to three days of thirty
minutes of exercise I will have to figure out.
</p><p>
The new place is a bit more than twice the size of the apartment I
currently have.  This brings its own set of things to think about. 
Mostly that I am quite sure I will feel a need to fill the space.  That
there would be one more money sink hole I am not so sure I need. 
Hopefully that one won't form some kind of repeating wallet weight loss
though.
</p><p>
There is a lot to look forward to as well.  Like having real central
air, both heating and cooling.  I really cannot express how much this
little piece excites me.  Living in this apartment that is older than I
has brought forth a great deal of appreciation for such advancements in
technology.  The other little bit that I'm quite ready for is being able
to fix little things.  The idea of being able to replace a faucet that
leaks, instead of watching maintenance just crank it down tight. 
(<small>Yes, it stopped leaking, however it now takes two hands to get
hot water out of that faucet.</small>)
</p><p>
All in all, this is being quite the neat experience.  The only lasting
bit of tension now is that I don't close until mid June.  So now I just
have to wait, knowing what is waiting for me.
</p>
            </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog//">
    <title>Shredding Paper</title>
    <link href="papershredding.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/http://tadpol.org/bog/papershredding.html</id>
    <published>2004-02-15T10:07:26-06:00</published>
    <updated>2011-03-23T14:02:32-05:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">





<p>
There is something frightenly grown up about buying a paper shredder. 
I'm not exactly sure what it is though.  Something to do with the
concept of not only having, but also being concerned with, documents
that you would rather others not read.  Which is entirely the part that
brings the frightening to play.
</p><p>
It is not like this ordeal with sensitive documents just jumped out and
bit me.  Its been here for quite sometime.  Somewhere around that first
credit card I think.  Or perhaps it was the University, with the piles
upon piles of documents and papers to be signed.  The whole don't share
your student ID with anyone, but could everyone please put it onto your
assignments next to your name so we know who you are thing. (<small>Run
sentence Run!</small>)  I might be able to pin this on the government
too, what with the paper storm that follows the shroud of taxes.  But
I'm just not fully sure when that actually started.
</p><p>
It is all the number of things that identify you by number, and solely
by that number.  Such that anyone with that number can be for all
practical purposes you.  So things become a race to destroy the numbers
before someone else can read them.  So we get a paper shredder, and hope
that no one has a roll of clear tape and enough patience to assemble the
shreds.
</p><p>
</p><p>
That and after a day the waste basket it came with is almost full.  Even
after compacting it a few times.  I'm quite sure that about half of that
did not need to be shredded.  Its just that, well, its fun to stick
paper in the shredder.  There is the massive growling noise and the way
the paper &lsquo;quivers&rsquo; as it is devoured.  Its just fun to
watch. <code>^_^</code>
</p>
            </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog//">
    <title>Noisy Silence</title>
    <link href="noisysilence.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/http://tadpol.org/bog/noisysilence.html</id>
    <published>2005-10-22T10:55:02-05:00</published>
    <updated>2011-03-23T14:02:31-05:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">


<p>There is so much stuff in my head that I might share, but I don&#8217;t.  Lots of reasons
for that, though the main one tends to be linked to difficultly.  Mostly in that
there isn&#8217;t anywhere to stage ideas.  Some place to play with them a bit and see
if they are worth sharing before I share.  So I&#8217;m aiming to change that.</p>

<p>This means an update to the site&#8217;s back end.  I&#8217;ve poked and prodded, testing various
different systems.  Some by others, some of my own design.  Lots of things to look
at, most not following my previous designs though.</p>

<p>This brings the first conclusion: Static only site is cute, but a waste.  Back 
in the day, it was almost required.  For what I was willing to pay, a machine that
could handle the load of generating every page on demand wasn&#8217;t worth it.  Not to 
mention that most of my site is static.  So I designed a system that made static
pages, and then uploaded those.</p>

<p>These days, a machine that can do the dynamics is around $400.  Less or more depending 
on how you play the sales and rebates games.  Plus that most of the dynamic
generation tools out there automatically build static caches.  So really, it is only 
the first hit of a page that costs.  This is very nice.</p>

<p>This now hinges things on the next bit.  For a site that is low traffic and mostly
static, <b>why</b> should I have a full running SQL daemon running?  Ick ick. <br />
I am probably being overly, unfairly biased against something I&#8217;m not used to using
here.  But I really don&#8217;t like running more than absolutely needed.  Which brings
in the nice touch of SQLite.  So, no worries there.</p>

<p>Well now, the thing with doing this much reworking on the back end, is that the 
front end needs work too.  So I might as well revamp that as well.  I&#8217;ve got a 
solid idea of what I want, I just have to figure out how to actually make it. <br />
My CG-fu is very weak.  So this is slowing things massively.  Oh well.</p>

<p>Then there is one last little detail.  The old data.  All of this.  Getting it 
into the new engine is easy.  Figured that out pretty quick.  There are a few parts
that won&#8217;t merge nicely, so I won&#8217;t bother.  They&#8217;re small, and work better the
way they are already anyways.  So there ends up being a static portion and the
dynamic portion of the site.  A little work with the Alias directive in the Apache
config, and you won&#8217;t even notice the separation.</p>

<p>So far quite good.  But a problem, I&#8217;ve pretty much just broken every single link.
I&#8217;m not sure what to do here.  I could try to Alias things over, but every post
will basically have a new link.  Lots of work to do things that way.  Worse is the 
amount of testing required to make sure its right, and I&#8217;ll miss something.  So 
that really doesn&#8217;t feel like the right answer.</p>

<p>What I will probably just do, is having the 404 page point people to a search box.
Maybe fill the search box with stuff based on the old link.  It could work.  It
still feels like a cop-out.  </p>

<p>So anyways.  I felt like I should put forth some kind of warning, not that it will
matter much.  Just gotta figure out those last couple of things&#8230;</p>
            </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog//">
    <title>New Indigo Battery</title>
    <link href="newindigobattery.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/http://tadpol.org/bog/newindigobattery.html</id>
    <published>2004-05-09T11:47:14-05:00</published>
    <updated>2011-03-23T14:02:31-05:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">


<p>
whee! I <em>finnally</em> got around to replacing the clock battery on
my Ingido R4k.  It has only been dead for about a year. (<small>High
importantce this machine has, can you not tell?</small>) Turns out to be
rather straight forward.  A little wheezy because the battery is
soldered down instead of socketed.  But that went pretty quick.  Super
helpful to have found some <a href="http://g-lenerz.de/sgistuff/documents/indigo-battery-faq.txt">
basic instructions</a> on what needed to be done.  Which was found with
google's help, since it isn't like the indigo gave a useful error,
&ldquo;Can't set tod clock.&rdquo;  Sounds kind of funny when you say it
aloud, but hardly points one in the direction of a dead battery. 
Anyways, the indigo boots now, and there is happiness.
</p>
<img src="../images/newindigobattery.jpg" height="240" alt="tools and motherboard" width="320" />

<p>There is something very oddly comforting to hear the whine of the SCSI2 drives in the old machine.  And at the same time, I know very well that in about an hour, the noise will start to drive me nuts.  The machine boots.  The clock is corrected.  It is halted, and packed away again.  I have no place but the middle of the floor for it right now.
</p>
<p>Perhaps I'll have a place for it in my new place.</p>
            </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog//">
    <title>My mind wonders</title>
    <link href="mindmeandersinjune.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/http://tadpol.org/bog/mindmeandersinjune.html</id>
    <published>2004-06-13T20:59:27-05:00</published>
    <updated>2011-03-23T14:02:31-05:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">


<p>
I'm tired, and I'm not doing anything.  It is a rather frustrating state
to be in.  Which nicely feeds back in on itself, and tires me more.  My
thoughts are highly disorganized, and this typically leads me to
silence. (<small>Since from disorganized thoughts, comes disorganized
speech.  Talking in that manor, causes others to question you, rightly
since you're not making sense.  That questioning is tiring to answer. 
Therefor, talking to others in this state causes me to dig deeper into
this state.  ick.</small>) But I feel, at the same time, a need to
ramble here a bit.  So I am.
</p><p>
Now, while I'm not doing much, I do have much that is happening.  Odd
how that works itself at times.  Sitting still, one becomes more active
than if they ran.  Life is sputtering in and out of things that need
doing and need thinking about.  Like moving and travel.
</p><p>
I will be entering the realms of <a href="townhome.html">homeowners</a> end of this week.  I do
not <em>directly</em> feel anything from this.  But there are many signs
that clearly describe otherwise.  Mostly my dislike of moving my things
coupled into the fact that I quite clearly need to be moving them.  This
is clear from the repetitious conversation with others, &ldquo;Have you
started packing yet?&rdquo;, &ldquo;No, I haven't really thought much
about it.&rdquo;  Over and over.  I should, probably, think about it
more.
</p><p>
One must understand, while moving bothers me, travel does not.  I love
going places, mostly empty places.  I already have two trips to the <a href="http://www.boundarywaterscanoearea.com/">Boundary Waters</a> lined
up for this summer, plus a trip to the <a href="http://www.rei.com/adventures/trips/namer/akarctic.html">middle of
Alaska</a>.  I found I quite enjoy going to places that people tend not
to go. (<small><a href="../vacation/antarctica/index.html">Antarctica</a>
for example.</small>)  This has always made sense to me, why visit a
city when you live in one?
</p><p>
I find my tolerance for people waning again. (<small>yes, again. it
cycles. actually there are cycles in the cycles.</small>)  Partially
shown in travel, mostly shown in activity.  I have been overly seeking
singular activities of late.  This doesn't bother me. (<small>it seems
to bother others.</small>)
</p><p>
I recently come upon a reference of a book about this.  (<small>I don't
remember where I read about the book, I was searching for tea.</small>) 
<em>Party of One: The Loners' Manifesto</em> by Anneli Rufus. 
Spectacular book, though there are many bits I disagree with.  Warm
places better for loners than cold?  Yes, everyone knows you are at home
when its cold, but they cannot visit.  When its warm they can always
just drop by.  There are others, but that is one that sticks to my head.
 But this is expected since loners, by their nature, are hard to
categorize. (<small>except of course that they all tend to fall out of
the crowd.</small>)
</p><p>
This book, being in the psychology section, has lead to all sorts of new
discoveries.  So many interesting books, I hardly know where to go from
here.  So I grabbed a book on manic-depression, seemed the thing to do. 
<em>Touched with Fire</em> by Kay Redfield Jamison.  Just started
working through this one, being filled with the full vocabulary, its a
bit slower reading.  Nifty though how the author is making ties between
manic-depression and artistic skills.  Even so, I don't think I'll take
this one traveling.  I like to relax, and this book is working my brain.
</p><p>
Then within all this, I've got the handful of projects.  A strategy
game, and some fixes to the under workings of my web site.  Both of
which have been neglected.  (<small>well, to some extent, the web site
obviously works without the changes I want.  And until I can get some
people together to play test the current idea, the game is going
nowhere.</small>)  So I want to work on those, at which point I realize
the sun has fitted itself to bed, and I have not done anything about my
move.  <b>oi</b>.
</p>
            </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog//">
    <title>I can See</title>
    <link href="I_can_see.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/http://tadpol.org/bog/I_can_see.html</id>
    <published>2001-12-07T16:34:46-06:00</published>
    <updated>2011-03-23T14:02:30-05:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">



<p>
Fun fun.  I have glasses.  Need them for far away stuff.  You know stuff that's like eight feet out or so.  It started getting blurry there, and got worse the farther out things were.  Don't ask how I was driving.  Thankfully that was only once in a great while.  Being that I walk most places. (<small>Or bum rides.</small>)  Driving back from getting glasses was dangerous enough though, I was spending more time looking at all of the stuff that used to be a big blurry blobs, instead of the cars in front of me.  Heh, oopies.
</p>
<p>
Spendy little things glasses are.  When I saw the first of the bill, I was all about increasing it by an eighth for a two year warranty. (<small>bring in the pieces, and they replace for free.  Nice deal i think.</small>)  That and got the anti-reflection, crap-did-the-lenses-fall-out-I-cannot-tell coating.  The frames I got a nifty since they come with clip-on shades.  But they don't clip, there is little magnets in the glasses and shade parts.  When they get close; they go <b>stick!</b>  It's great fun, I wasted a good chunk of time just putting the shades on, and taking them off again.  (<small>But I'm easily amused like that.</small>)
</p>
<p>
Trying to get into the habit of wearing them all the time.  Since I'm apt to forget them completely otherwise.  Which complicates, since I don't need glasses for close up work, and I have those BA poofy headphones at work.  And they and the glasses don't mix all that well.  So I'm always taking my glasses off when I'm at my desk.  Ah well.  At least I remember to put them back on when I get up.  (<small>If I don't, I usually remember really quick.</small>)
</p>
<p>
That and it is going to take some getting used to having these lines in my vision.  Having the edges of the frames right there is different.  More so when I'm seeing things close, because it is all in focus then.  And it gets slightly frusterating to look down at something quick that is out of the focus range.  Then have to stop doing it quick, because I need to move my whole head so that the glasses move with my vision instead of moving just my head.
</p>
<p>
As such, I am noticing how much I actually look out of the sides of my eyes, rather than moving my head.  Walking to work for example.  I didn't realise that I usually walk with my head down a bit, and look out the top of my eyes.  Cannot do that with glasses, since I am looking over the top of them then.  Kind of useless that way.  Is weird getting used to holding my head up straight while walking.  Also makes me wonder how often I do stuff like that.  And what it makes me look like to others. (<small>hehee, this is probably an improvement then. <code>^_^</code></small>)
</p>
<p>Anyways, this is then, what I look like with glasses: <br />
<img src="../images/MikeinGlasses.jpg" height="257" width="384" />
</p>
            </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog//">
    <title>Is it wrong to Hop?</title>
    <link href="hopping.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/http://tadpol.org/bog/hopping.html</id>
    <published>2004-02-08T20:39:21-06:00</published>
    <updated>2011-03-23T14:02:29-05:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">



<p>
Is it wrong to hop?<br />
With your hair in pig-tails<br />
To feel it bounce next to your ears<br />
As your entire body rebounds<br />
From hitting the floor.
</p>


<object height="120" classid="clsid:02BF25D5-8C17-4B23-BC80-D3488ABDDC6B" codebase="http://www.apple.com/qtactivex/qtplugin.cab" width="160">
<param name="AUTOPLAY" value="true" />
<param name="CONTROLLER" value="TRUE" />
<param name="pluginspage" value="http://www.apple.com/quicktime/download/indext.html" />
<param name="target" value="myself" />
<param name="type" value="video/quicktime" />
<param name="SRC" value="../moovs/hopping.mov" />
<embed kioskmode="TRUE" pluginspage="http://www.apple.com/quicktime/download/indext.html" src="../moovs/hopping.mov" border="0" autoplay="TRUE" height="120" target="myself" controller="TRUE" width="160">
</embed></object>

            </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="projects//">
    <title>Tadpol's Calculator v3</title>
    <link href="Tadpol_s_Calculator.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/http://tadpol.org/projects/Tadpol_s_Calculator.html</id>
    <published>2009-01-24T09:07:09-06:00</published>
    <updated>2009-12-22T20:18:12-06:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<p>There is a saying about dog food and eating it.  So after a bit I started to find my little calculator lacking.  Quite severely in some places; so I gave it a redesign.  Twice.</p>

<p>A quick person will note that this is version 3 and the previous was version 1, thus skipping version 2.  There was a version 2.  It had the same GUI as version 1, but it was a full out RPN.  There were multiple stacks that were named.  Those stacks were also little programs; letting you program the calculator.  It was all very nifty by design.  It was utterly worthless to use.</p>

<p>Version 2 was a key lesson for designing version 3.</p>

<p>As a programmer, the stacks are a very neat concept.  For doing little quick bits of math, they interfere.  The real reason for the stack though, was that your basic calculator only has one extra bit of memory.  I find that too limiting.  I played around and tested a few things and found that I never really used more than three or four memory cells.  So version 3 has five memory cells.</p>

<p>The ability to write little programs for the calc was a neat idea that I never used.  TadpolCalc is written in TCL, it is far easier to just add functions in TCL that any little toy language.  Never mind the detail that it was a feature that never got used.  Version 3 doesn&#8217;t try to have its own programming language.</p>

<p>Version 1 and 2 had broken fixed number modes.  That bug is squished in version 3.</p>

<p>There were a lot of funny key collisions in version 1.  Try entering a hexadecimal number in all caps.  Goes ok until you get to a &#8216;B&#8217;.  Version 3 isn&#8217;t quite as crazy about single key shortcuts.</p>

<p>I aslo finally figured out how to convert a floating point number into hexadecimal.  I&#8217;m mildly ashamed it took me so long.  IEEE defined how to do this, thus that is the way to do it.  (<small>And that one memory dump with floats in it that I needed to decode also helped push the matter.</small>)  Converting floats to hexadecimal and binary actually works in version 3.</p>

<p>So here is my latest version; something I find useful again.  We&#8217;ll see how this one stands after a bit of time.  </p>

<p>Oh, one thing, Control-? for help. (<small>or on most keyboards, Control-Shift-/</small>)</p>

<p>(<small>and yes, I am in fact finding little things to fix already.</small>)</p>

<p>Screenshots:<br />
<img src="images/tc-mac-v3.png" height="123" width="349" />&nbsp;&nbsp;
<!-- img src="/projects/images/tc-win-v3.png" / --></p>

<p>Download:
 - <a href="/projects/archives/tadpolcalc/tadpolcalc-darwin-univ-aqua-v3.zip">Macintosh</a>
 - <a href="/projects/archives/tadpolcalc/tadpolcalc-win32-v3.zip">Windows</a>
 - <a href="/projects/archives/tadpolcalc/tadpolcalc-linux-x86-v3.zip">Linux</a>
 - <a href="/projects/archives/tadpolcalc/tadpolcalc-kit-v3.zip">kit</a></p>
            </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="projects//">
    <title>Tadpol's Calculator</title>
    <link href="Tadpol_s_Calculator_v1.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/http://tadpol.org/projects/Tadpol_s_Calculator_v1.html</id>
    <published>2009-01-24T09:07:09-06:00</published>
    <updated>2009-12-22T19:45:36-06:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<p>This is a little calculator app I worte up to better fit my needs than a typical default one. It has a few features that I found I wanted.</p>

<p>First thing most noticable is that there are no little gui buttons.  Everything is reachable from the keyboard, so I see no reason to build a bunch of buttons that just get in the way.</p>

<p>It has a stack for memory storage, and is used in completing operations. Even though there is a stack, the calculator is not postfix notation.  All operations are still infix.  This might seem a little odd, but I find it works quite well.  You have the stack for doing some really deep stuff, but its all still infix which just seems more natural. (<small>my opinion anyhows.</small>)</p>

<p>It supports labeling decimal numbers using most of the SI standard labels. (<small>The exception is deka- for which the official label is da, but I use D instead. By doing this all the labels are a single character.</small>)  Decimal and floating point numbers can be labeled, just type the label character in last.  Hex, Oct, and Bin numbers cannot be labeled.  The ‘best’ label for a number can also be calculated.</p>

<p>Numbers of different formats can be typed in at any time.  You do not have to switch to hex mode to insert a hex number.  Flip side to this is that hex, oct, and bin need to be prefixed with 0x, 0o, and 0b.</p>

<p>Screenshots:<br />
<img src="images/tc-mac.png" height="245" width="292" />&nbsp;&nbsp;
<img src="images/tc-win.png" height="316" width="232" /></p>

<p>Download:
 - <a href="/projects/archives/tadpolcalc/tadpolcalc-darwin-univ-aqua-3.zip">Macintosh</a>
 - <a href="/projects/archives/tadpolcalc/tadpolcalc-win32-3.zip">Windows</a>
 - <a href="/projects/archives/tadpolcalc/tadpolcalc-linux-x86-3.zip">Linux</a></p>
            </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog//">
    <title>Life Changes</title>
    <link href="lifeChange.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/http://tadpol.org/bog/lifeChange.html</id>
    <published>2009-11-10T18:35:05-06:00</published>
    <updated>2009-11-23T19:45:43-06:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<p>People say it many times, but it is meaningless until it happens to you.  Having a baby changes everything.  There are a fair amount of things I want to do, and posting updates to this site falls to the bottom.  There is a redesign pending because of this, but I&#8217;m busy on other things.  Basically, moving away from the blog style to something I used way back when.</p>

<p>There, changed.</p>
            </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="recipes//">
    <title>Honey Curry Chicken Supper</title>
    <link href="Honey_Curry_Chicken.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/http://tadpol.org/recipes/Honey_Curry_Chicken.html</id>
    <published>2009-07-19T21:04:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2009-07-20T20:07:57-05:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<p><a href="../images/honeycurrychicken.jpg" class="thickbox" rel="recipesHoney_Curry_Chickenhtml"><img src="../images/honeycurrychicken_tn.jpg" height="240" width="320" /></a></p>

<table class="recipe">
  <tr>
    <td>Amount</td>
    <td>Measure</td>
    <td>Ingredient &#8212; Preparation</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>1</td>
    <td>lb</td>
    <td>
chicken breasts    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>1</td>
    <td>tbsp</td>
    <td>
olive oil    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>2</td>
    <td>tbsp</td>
    <td>
honey    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>1</td>
    <td>tbsp</td>
    <td>
citrus juice — orange, lime, lemon, whatever.    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>1</td>
    <td>tsp</td>
    <td>
Dijon Mustard    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>&#8531;</td>
    <td>tsp</td>
    <td>
salt    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>&#8531;</td>
    <td>tsp</td>
    <td>
curry powder    </td>
  </tr>
</table>


<p>Pre-heat oven to 350°F.  Place thawed chicken breasts into a glass baking dish.  Mix remaining ingredients and pour over chicken, coating all pieces well.  Bake for about 30 min, turning breasts over every 10 minutes or so.</p>

<table class="recipe">
  <tr>
    <td>Amount</td>
    <td>Measure</td>
    <td>Ingredient &#8212; Preparation</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>2</td>
    <td></td>
    <td>
zucchini — sliced    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>1</td>
    <td></td>
    <td>
yellow squash — sliced    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>1</td>
    <td>tsp</td>
    <td>
salt    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td>1</td>
    <td>tsp</td>
    <td>
dried parsley flakes    </td>
  </tr>
</table>


<p>Sprinkle salt over all of the slices.  Add to microwave safe dish with a quarter or so cup of water.  Zap for about 5 minutes, and drain.  Add parsley and toss lightly.</p>

<p>The mashed potatoes were instant, so you can just go read the box.</p>
            </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
