<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:base="http://tadpol.org/feed.atom" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Tadpol's bog</title>
  <id>http://tadpol.org/feed.atom</id>
  <link href="feed.atom" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tadpol.org" rel="alternate"/>
  <icon>/favicon.ico</icon>
  <updated>2012-01-23T14:19:53-06:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Michael Conrad Tadpol Tilstra</name>
  </author>
  <rights>All rights reserved.</rights>
  <generator>WebSpace 0.1 ruby code written by Michael Conrad Tadpol Tilstra</generator>
  <entry xml:base="bog/">
    <title>I bought a Town Home</title>
    <link href="townhome.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/bog/townhome.html</id>
    <published>2004-03-23T19:09:20-06:00</published>
    <updated>2011-03-23T14:02:34-05:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">


<p>
It is a very strange surreal feeling.  The combinational effect of not
only buying something this big, but that someone is willing to give me
the money for it.  Or something like that.  Clearly, if I fail to pay
up, they just take the house back.  But I'm not really thinking about
that.  Too far gone in the mind.  The house is mine.
(<small>sorta</small>)
</p><p>
The one thing in the process that still is somewhat amazing is the
amount of paper work.  Or rather, the volumes of things that I must sign
or initial.  I think I shall be most forever entertained by getting a
document that says that I was in fact told about another document. 
Signing the first to proved that I was truly in fact told about the next
document.  Being given the next document immediately after signing the
prior, and signing it.  Its just funny in an odd sort of way.
</p><p>
Amidst the excitement there are a few standing concerns at the moment. 
Oddly, the largest of which is that I'll now be far enough out that I
will have to commute via car or bus.  No longer close enough to work to
walk when the weather permits.  The important thing here is that it is
not the commute that is bothering me, it is that I'll lose my free
exercise of walking about thirty minutes a day.
</p><p>
I will have to be diligent once moved.  Most probably in a combination
of doing exercise just to exercise, and eating less than I do now.  I am
not too worried about the eating, I have always been rather good at just
stopping when I felt full.  (<small>It has never bothered me to leave
food on my plate.  When I'm done eating, I'm done.</small>)  It is the
whole remembering to take to move a bunch.
</p><p>
And this is where I'm hoping my new location that will be roughly the
right distance from book stores and the like.  The distance being just
enough that it is exercise to walk there, but not so much that it feels
overly far away to travel by foot.  So I figure I'm ok at least one day
of the week.  It is then the remaining two to three days of thirty
minutes of exercise I will have to figure out.
</p><p>
The new place is a bit more than twice the size of the apartment I
currently have.  This brings its own set of things to think about. 
Mostly that I am quite sure I will feel a need to fill the space.  That
there would be one more money sink hole I am not so sure I need. 
Hopefully that one won't form some kind of repeating wallet weight loss
though.
</p><p>
There is a lot to look forward to as well.  Like having real central
air, both heating and cooling.  I really cannot express how much this
little piece excites me.  Living in this apartment that is older than I
has brought forth a great deal of appreciation for such advancements in
technology.  The other little bit that I'm quite ready for is being able
to fix little things.  The idea of being able to replace a faucet that
leaks, instead of watching maintenance just crank it down tight. 
(<small>Yes, it stopped leaking, however it now takes two hands to get
hot water out of that faucet.</small>)
</p><p>
All in all, this is being quite the neat experience.  The only lasting
bit of tension now is that I don't close until mid June.  So now I just
have to wait, knowing what is waiting for me.
</p>
      </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog/">
    <title>Shredding Paper</title>
    <link href="papershredding.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/bog/papershredding.html</id>
    <published>2004-02-15T10:07:26-06:00</published>
    <updated>2011-03-23T14:02:32-05:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">




<p>
There is something frightenly grown up about buying a paper shredder. 
I'm not exactly sure what it is though.  Something to do with the
concept of not only having, but also being concerned with, documents
that you would rather others not read.  Which is entirely the part that
brings the frightening to play.
</p><p>
It is not like this ordeal with sensitive documents just jumped out and
bit me.  Its been here for quite sometime.  Somewhere around that first
credit card I think.  Or perhaps it was the University, with the piles
upon piles of documents and papers to be signed.  The whole don't share
your student ID with anyone, but could everyone please put it onto your
assignments next to your name so we know who you are thing. (<small>Run
sentence Run!</small>)  I might be able to pin this on the government
too, what with the paper storm that follows the shroud of taxes.  But
I'm just not fully sure when that actually started.
</p><p>
It is all the number of things that identify you by number, and solely
by that number.  Such that anyone with that number can be for all
practical purposes you.  So things become a race to destroy the numbers
before someone else can read them.  So we get a paper shredder, and hope
that no one has a roll of clear tape and enough patience to assemble the
shreds.
</p><p>
</p><p>
That and after a day the waste basket it came with is almost full.  Even
after compacting it a few times.  I'm quite sure that about half of that
did not need to be shredded.  Its just that, well, its fun to stick
paper in the shredder.  There is the massive growling noise and the way
the paper &lsquo;quivers&rsquo; as it is devoured.  Its just fun to
watch. <code>^_^</code>
</p>
      </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog/">
    <title>My mind wonders</title>
    <link href="mindmeandersinjune.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/bog/mindmeandersinjune.html</id>
    <published>2004-06-13T20:59:27-05:00</published>
    <updated>2011-03-23T14:02:31-05:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<p>
I'm tired, and I'm not doing anything.  It is a rather frustrating state
to be in.  Which nicely feeds back in on itself, and tires me more.  My
thoughts are highly disorganized, and this typically leads me to
silence. (<small>Since from disorganized thoughts, comes disorganized
speech.  Talking in that manor, causes others to question you, rightly
since you're not making sense.  That questioning is tiring to answer. 
Therefor, talking to others in this state causes me to dig deeper into
this state.  ick.</small>) But I feel, at the same time, a need to
ramble here a bit.  So I am.
</p><p>
Now, while I'm not doing much, I do have much that is happening.  Odd
how that works itself at times.  Sitting still, one becomes more active
than if they ran.  Life is sputtering in and out of things that need
doing and need thinking about.  Like moving and travel.
</p><p>
I will be entering the realms of <a href="townhome.html">homeowners</a> end of this week.  I do
not <em>directly</em> feel anything from this.  But there are many signs
that clearly describe otherwise.  Mostly my dislike of moving my things
coupled into the fact that I quite clearly need to be moving them.  This
is clear from the repetitious conversation with others, &ldquo;Have you
started packing yet?&rdquo;, &ldquo;No, I haven't really thought much
about it.&rdquo;  Over and over.  I should, probably, think about it
more.
</p><p>
One must understand, while moving bothers me, travel does not.  I love
going places, mostly empty places.  I already have two trips to the <a href="http://www.boundarywaterscanoearea.com/">Boundary Waters</a> lined
up for this summer, plus a trip to the <a href="http://www.rei.com/adventures/trips/namer/akarctic.html">middle of
Alaska</a>.  I found I quite enjoy going to places that people tend not
to go. (<small><a href="../vacation/antarctica/index.html">Antarctica</a>
for example.</small>)  This has always made sense to me, why visit a
city when you live in one?
</p><p>
I find my tolerance for people waning again. (<small>yes, again. it
cycles. actually there are cycles in the cycles.</small>)  Partially
shown in travel, mostly shown in activity.  I have been overly seeking
singular activities of late.  This doesn't bother me. (<small>it seems
to bother others.</small>)
</p><p>
I recently come upon a reference of a book about this.  (<small>I don't
remember where I read about the book, I was searching for tea.</small>) 
<em>Party of One: The Loners' Manifesto</em> by Anneli Rufus. 
Spectacular book, though there are many bits I disagree with.  Warm
places better for loners than cold?  Yes, everyone knows you are at home
when its cold, but they cannot visit.  When its warm they can always
just drop by.  There are others, but that is one that sticks to my head.
 But this is expected since loners, by their nature, are hard to
categorize. (<small>except of course that they all tend to fall out of
the crowd.</small>)
</p><p>
This book, being in the psychology section, has lead to all sorts of new
discoveries.  So many interesting books, I hardly know where to go from
here.  So I grabbed a book on manic-depression, seemed the thing to do. 
<em>Touched with Fire</em> by Kay Redfield Jamison.  Just started
working through this one, being filled with the full vocabulary, its a
bit slower reading.  Nifty though how the author is making ties between
manic-depression and artistic skills.  Even so, I don't think I'll take
this one traveling.  I like to relax, and this book is working my brain.
</p><p>
Then within all this, I've got the handful of projects.  A strategy
game, and some fixes to the under workings of my web site.  Both of
which have been neglected.  (<small>well, to some extent, the web site
obviously works without the changes I want.  And until I can get some
people together to play test the current idea, the game is going
nowhere.</small>)  So I want to work on those, at which point I realize
the sun has fitted itself to bed, and I have not done anything about my
move.  <b>oi</b>.
</p>
      </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog/">
    <title>Noisy Silence</title>
    <link href="noisysilence.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/bog/noisysilence.html</id>
    <published>2005-10-22T10:55:02-05:00</published>
    <updated>2011-03-23T14:02:31-05:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<p>There is so much stuff in my head that I might share, but I don&#8217;t.  Lots of reasons
for that, though the main one tends to be linked to difficultly.  Mostly in that
there isn&#8217;t anywhere to stage ideas.  Some place to play with them a bit and see
if they are worth sharing before I share.  So I&#8217;m aiming to change that.</p>

<p>This means an update to the site&#8217;s back end.  I&#8217;ve poked and prodded, testing various
different systems.  Some by others, some of my own design.  Lots of things to look
at, most not following my previous designs though.</p>

<p>This brings the first conclusion: Static only site is cute, but a waste.  Back 
in the day, it was almost required.  For what I was willing to pay, a machine that
could handle the load of generating every page on demand wasn&#8217;t worth it.  Not to 
mention that most of my site is static.  So I designed a system that made static
pages, and then uploaded those.</p>

<p>These days, a machine that can do the dynamics is around $400.  Less or more depending 
on how you play the sales and rebates games.  Plus that most of the dynamic
generation tools out there automatically build static caches.  So really, it is only 
the first hit of a page that costs.  This is very nice.</p>

<p>This now hinges things on the next bit.  For a site that is low traffic and mostly
static, <b>why</b> should I have a full running SQL daemon running?  Ick ick. <br />
I am probably being overly, unfairly biased against something I&#8217;m not used to using
here.  But I really don&#8217;t like running more than absolutely needed.  Which brings
in the nice touch of SQLite.  So, no worries there.</p>

<p>Well now, the thing with doing this much reworking on the back end, is that the 
front end needs work too.  So I might as well revamp that as well.  I&#8217;ve got a 
solid idea of what I want, I just have to figure out how to actually make it. <br />
My CG-fu is very weak.  So this is slowing things massively.  Oh well.</p>

<p>Then there is one last little detail.  The old data.  All of this.  Getting it 
into the new engine is easy.  Figured that out pretty quick.  There are a few parts
that won&#8217;t merge nicely, so I won&#8217;t bother.  They&#8217;re small, and work better the
way they are already anyways.  So there ends up being a static portion and the
dynamic portion of the site.  A little work with the Alias directive in the Apache
config, and you won&#8217;t even notice the separation.</p>

<p>So far quite good.  But a problem, I&#8217;ve pretty much just broken every single link.
I&#8217;m not sure what to do here.  I could try to Alias things over, but every post
will basically have a new link.  Lots of work to do things that way.  Worse is the 
amount of testing required to make sure its right, and I&#8217;ll miss something.  So 
that really doesn&#8217;t feel like the right answer.</p>

<p>What I will probably just do, is having the 404 page point people to a search box.
Maybe fill the search box with stuff based on the old link.  It could work.  It
still feels like a cop-out.  </p>

<p>So anyways.  I felt like I should put forth some kind of warning, not that it will
matter much.  Just gotta figure out those last couple of things&#8230;</p>
      </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog/">
    <title>New Indigo Battery</title>
    <link href="newindigobattery.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/bog/newindigobattery.html</id>
    <published>2004-05-09T11:47:14-05:00</published>
    <updated>2011-03-23T14:02:31-05:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<p>
whee! I <em>finnally</em> got around to replacing the clock battery on
my Ingido R4k.  It has only been dead for about a year. (<small>High
importantce this machine has, can you not tell?</small>) Turns out to be
rather straight forward.  A little wheezy because the battery is
soldered down instead of socketed.  But that went pretty quick.  Super
helpful to have found some <a href="http://g-lenerz.de/sgistuff/documents/indigo-battery-faq.txt">
basic instructions</a> on what needed to be done.  Which was found with
google's help, since it isn't like the indigo gave a useful error,
&ldquo;Can't set tod clock.&rdquo;  Sounds kind of funny when you say it
aloud, but hardly points one in the direction of a dead battery. 
Anyways, the indigo boots now, and there is happiness.
</p>
<img src="../images/newindigobattery.jpg" height="240" alt="tools and motherboard" width="320" />

<p>There is something very oddly comforting to hear the whine of the SCSI2 drives in the old machine.  And at the same time, I know very well that in about an hour, the noise will start to drive me nuts.  The machine boots.  The clock is corrected.  It is halted, and packed away again.  I have no place but the middle of the floor for it right now.
</p>
<p>Perhaps I'll have a place for it in my new place.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog/">
    <title>I can See</title>
    <link href="I_can_see.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/bog/I_can_see.html</id>
    <published>2001-12-07T16:34:46-06:00</published>
    <updated>2011-03-23T14:02:30-05:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">


<p>
Fun fun.  I have glasses.  Need them for far away stuff.  You know stuff that's like eight feet out or so.  It started getting blurry there, and got worse the farther out things were.  Don't ask how I was driving.  Thankfully that was only once in a great while.  Being that I walk most places. (<small>Or bum rides.</small>)  Driving back from getting glasses was dangerous enough though, I was spending more time looking at all of the stuff that used to be a big blurry blobs, instead of the cars in front of me.  Heh, oopies.
</p>
<p>
Spendy little things glasses are.  When I saw the first of the bill, I was all about increasing it by an eighth for a two year warranty. (<small>bring in the pieces, and they replace for free.  Nice deal i think.</small>)  That and got the anti-reflection, crap-did-the-lenses-fall-out-I-cannot-tell coating.  The frames I got a nifty since they come with clip-on shades.  But they don't clip, there is little magnets in the glasses and shade parts.  When they get close; they go <b>stick!</b>  It's great fun, I wasted a good chunk of time just putting the shades on, and taking them off again.  (<small>But I'm easily amused like that.</small>)
</p>
<p>
Trying to get into the habit of wearing them all the time.  Since I'm apt to forget them completely otherwise.  Which complicates, since I don't need glasses for close up work, and I have those BA poofy headphones at work.  And they and the glasses don't mix all that well.  So I'm always taking my glasses off when I'm at my desk.  Ah well.  At least I remember to put them back on when I get up.  (<small>If I don't, I usually remember really quick.</small>)
</p>
<p>
That and it is going to take some getting used to having these lines in my vision.  Having the edges of the frames right there is different.  More so when I'm seeing things close, because it is all in focus then.  And it gets slightly frusterating to look down at something quick that is out of the focus range.  Then have to stop doing it quick, because I need to move my whole head so that the glasses move with my vision instead of moving just my head.
</p>
<p>
As such, I am noticing how much I actually look out of the sides of my eyes, rather than moving my head.  Walking to work for example.  I didn't realise that I usually walk with my head down a bit, and look out the top of my eyes.  Cannot do that with glasses, since I am looking over the top of them then.  Kind of useless that way.  Is weird getting used to holding my head up straight while walking.  Also makes me wonder how often I do stuff like that.  And what it makes me look like to others. (<small>hehee, this is probably an improvement then. <code>^_^</code></small>)
</p>
<p>Anyways, this is then, what I look like with glasses: <br />
<img src="../images/MikeinGlasses.jpg" height="257" width="384" />
</p>
      </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog/">
    <title>Is it wrong to Hop?</title>
    <link href="hopping.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/bog/hopping.html</id>
    <published>2004-02-08T20:39:21-06:00</published>
    <updated>2011-03-23T14:02:29-05:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">


<p>
Is it wrong to hop?<br />
With your hair in pig-tails<br />
To feel it bounce next to your ears<br />
As your entire body rebounds<br />
From hitting the floor.
</p>


<object height="120" classid="clsid:02BF25D5-8C17-4B23-BC80-D3488ABDDC6B" codebase="http://www.apple.com/qtactivex/qtplugin.cab" width="160">
<param name="AUTOPLAY" value="true" />
<param name="CONTROLLER" value="TRUE" />
<param name="pluginspage" value="http://www.apple.com/quicktime/download/indext.html" />
<param name="target" value="myself" />
<param name="type" value="video/quicktime" />
<param name="SRC" value="../moovs/hopping.mov" />
<embed kioskmode="TRUE" pluginspage="http://www.apple.com/quicktime/download/indext.html" src="../moovs/hopping.mov" border="0" autoplay="TRUE" height="120" target="myself" controller="TRUE" width="160">
</embed></object>

      </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog/">
    <title>Life Changes</title>
    <link href="lifeChange.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/bog/lifeChange.html</id>
    <published>2009-11-10T18:35:05-06:00</published>
    <updated>2009-11-23T19:45:43-06:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>People say it many times, but it is meaningless until it happens to you.  Having a baby changes everything.  There are a fair amount of things I want to do, and posting updates to this site falls to the bottom.  There is a redesign pending because of this, but I&#8217;m busy on other things.  Basically, moving away from the blog style to something I used way back when.</p>

<p>There, changed.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog/">
    <title>My Daddy's a Geek</title>
    <link href="My_Daddy_s_a_Geek.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/bog/My_Daddy_s_a_Geek.html</id>
    <published>2009-06-21T13:53:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2009-06-21T13:53:25-05:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p><img src="../images/mydaddyisageek.jpg" height="640" width="480" />
<br />
Its true, I am.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog/">
    <title>Simple Flash Trick</title>
    <link href="Simple_Flash_Trick.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/bog/Simple_Flash_Trick.html</id>
    <published>2008-01-30T21:53:39-06:00</published>
    <updated>2009-02-18T21:08:37-06:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Simple little things I discovered while trying to take some close up pictures of a <a href="http://mindstorms.lego.com/">Technics model</a>.  There is a lot of white shiny plastic parts in the set, so it pretty much always washes out with the flash.  Solution is to cover the bottom half of the flash with my finger.  Had to use my cell phone to take a picture of my camera, but a picture really shows what I mean best.</p>

<p><a href="../images/fingerOverFlash.jpg" class="thickbox" rel="simpleflashtrick"><img src="../images/fingerOverFlash_tn.jpg" height="96" width="128" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Updated: 2008-02-04T19:10:59-06:00</strong> </p>

<p>So you can see, here are two shots using this trick. First without, then with.  Definitely falls under the hack/kludge category, but good enough for what I needed.</p>

<p><a href="../images/FullFlash.jpg" class="thickbox" rel="simpleflashtrick"><img src="../images/FullFlash_tn.jpg" height="113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="../images/HalfFlash.jpg" class="thickbox" rel="simpleflashtrick"><img src="../images/HalfFlash_tn.jpg" height="113" width="150" /></a></p>
      </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog/">
    <title>Hurrah! Snow!</title>
    <link href="Hurrah_Snow_2007.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/bog/Hurrah_Snow_2007.html</id>
    <published>2007-03-02T09:26:30-06:00</published>
    <updated>2009-02-18T08:18:54-06:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>We have about a foot and a half of snow! eeeee!</p>

<p><img src="../images/snow_on_bushes_2007.jpg" height="320" width="240" />
<img src="../images/snow_on_doorstep_2007.jpg" height="320" width="240" /></p>

<p>I would like to add, that the mini-alvalanches off of the roof onto the sidewalk and patio below are providing me with bursts of random amusement throughout the day.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog/">
    <title>First Set Designed</title>
    <link href="First_Set_Designed.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/bog/First_Set_Designed.html</id>
    <published>2008-01-08T19:33:06-06:00</published>
    <updated>2009-02-18T08:17:02-06:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>While poking around looking for ideas to mess with my <a href="http://mindstorms.lego.com/">NXT</a>, I happened across <a href="http://ldd.lego.com/">LEGO Digital Designer</a>.  I had heard of it before, but never really thought much of it.  Not having much else I wanted to do, I downloaded it.  Figuring that I would at least use up a couple hours trying to model some <a href="http://mindstorms.lego.com/">NXT</a> sets.  And so I played, and it was fun.</p>

<p>I should mention here that I also follow <a href="http://www.brothers-brick.com/">Brothers Brick</a>, and the posts about <a href="http://www.brothers-brick.com/2007/12/14/rainbow-warriors/">mini-spaceships</a> always caught my eye.  This naturally came to mind while I was playing with <a href="http://ldd.lego.com/">LDD</a>.  So I gave a go at building some. Pretty easy in <a href="http://ldd.lego.com/">LDD</a>.  There had been a handful of warnings here and there about part selection that I was, up until this point, happily ignoring.</p>

<p>There is this little icon on the tool bar, of a brick and a globe and an arrow connecting the two.  I was curious.  I am really trying to imagine how I was supposed to say no when I got bounced to a web page asking if I would like to buy the set I just designed.  I mean really.  Design my own set and get the parts for it without having to scrounge them from other sets? Totally must do, totally.</p>

<p>So I did.</p>

<p>And here it is, unopened:<br /></p>

<p><a href="../images/firstLegoBox.jpg" class="thickbox" rel="lego"><img src="../images/firstLegoBox-s.jpg" height="113" width="150" /></a></p>

<p>Then built:<br /></p>

<p><a href="../images/firstLegos.jpg" class="thickbox" rel="lego"><img src="../images/firstLegos-s.jpg" height="113" width="150" /></a></p>
      </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog/">
    <title>Steam Passenger Train</title>
    <link href="Steam_Passenger_Train.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/bog/Steam_Passenger_Train.html</id>
    <published>2007-10-07T19:35:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2009-02-18T08:10:40-06:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>On my way back to the cities this weekend, I saw a steam passenger train running along the road.  So I grabbed my phone quick and took a couple of shots.  You can see that I&#8217;m doing this while trying to drive.  Watching all the other vehicles engaged in the similar activity only made it more entertaining.  (<small>and kinda scary since everyone wasn&#8217;t really watching each other, and there was quite the car-pack near the train.</small>)</p>

<p><a href="../images/steam-train-1b.jpg" class="thickbox" rel="train"><img src="../images/steam-train-1.jpg" height="240" width="320" /></a></p>

<p><a href="../images/steam-train-2b.jpg" class="thickbox" rel="train"><img src="../images/steam-train-2.jpg" height="240" width="320" /></a></p>
      </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog/">
    <title>First Christmas Tree</title>
    <link href="First_Christmas_Tree.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/bog/First_Christmas_Tree.html</id>
    <published>2008-12-07T18:19:11-06:00</published>
    <updated>2008-12-07T18:25:11-06:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>This is our first tree together, such fun.</p>

<p><a href="../images/FirstChristmasTree2008m.jpg" class="thickbox" rel="bogFirst_Christmas_Treehtml"><img src="../images/FirstChristmasTree2008s.jpg" height="320" width="240" /></a></p>

<p>With very neat LED lights that switch between multi-color and white. (<small>and which I cannot seem to find online anywhere.</small>)</p>
      </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="bog/">
    <title>itty bitty Halloween</title>
    <link href="itty_bitty_Holloween.html"/>
    <id>http://tadpol.org/bog/itty_bitty_Holloween.html</id>
    <published>2008-10-21T20:18:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2008-11-16T12:35:51-06:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Because small equals cute (<small>for a given definition of small</small>)</p>

<p><a href="../images/pumpkin2008m.jpg" class="thickbox" rel="bogitty_bitty_Holloweenhtml"><img src="../images/pumpkin2008s.jpg" height="240" width="320" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Updated: 2008-11-16T12:05:21-06:00</strong> </p>

<p>I took them to work, and after about a week, they looked like wrinkly old men.  (<small>Made me full of giggles.</small>)</p>

<p><a href="../images/pumpkin2008-old.jpg" class="thickbox" rel="bogitty_bitty_Holloweenhtml"><img src="../images/pumpkin2008-olds.jpg" height="240" width="320" /></a></p>
      </div>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
